RG 004:056, Granby Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Granby Probate Court records
1807-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Granby District)
32 cubic feet
Record books, 1807-1924; Probate files, 1807-1975.
RG004_056
1913-004, T003290, 2011-049, 2011-050
Historical Note
Granby, Hartford County, Town established in October 1786, Parent Town: Simsbury
The Granby Probate District was constituted May 1807 from the Simsbury Probate District. It also served the following municipalities at various times: East Granby, June 1858 - July 3, 1865; Hartland, May 1807 - June 2, 1836; and the part of Suffield lying west of the mountain, May 1807 - May 1821. The Granby Probate District merged on January 5, 2011 with the Avon, Canton, and Simsbury Probate Districts to create the Simsbury Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Avon, Canton, Granby, and Simsbury.
Town of Granby, Probate District chronology:
October 1786 - May 1807, Simsbury District
May 1807 - January 4, 2011, Granby District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Simsbury Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-16, 1807-1924. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 16.
Probate files, 1807-1975. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1807-1925 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 16.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1913-004 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-050.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - East Granby; Probate records -- Connecticut - Granby; Probate records -- Connecticut - Hartland; Probate records -- Connecticut - Suffield
Places:
East Granby (Conn.); Granby (Conn.); Hartland (Conn.); Suffield (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1975 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-049, Record books, 1807-1924; and Accession 2011-050, Probate files, 1912-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-16, 1807-1924; probate files 1807-1915 (Accession 1913-004 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 3, 1913 (1807-1913); October 18, 1935 (1885, 1911-1925). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-049 and the probate files in accession 2011-050 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 23, 2010.
It is not known when the probate files in accession T003290 was transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Record books, 1807-1924; 10.6 cubic feet (16 volumes); 2011-049
  - Records, 1807-1813 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1803-1819 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1818-1825 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1825-1831 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1831-1835 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1835-1837 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1837-1844 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1842-1850 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1840-1857 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1856-1864 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1864-1873 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1873-1885 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1885-1897 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1895-1910 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1906-1916 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1914-1924 (Volume 16)
- Probate files, 1807-1925; 11 cubic feet; 1913-004
  - Abel - Baldwin (Drawer 1)
  - Banning - Beebe (Drawer 2)
  - Beman - Buttles (Drawer 3)
  - Cake-bread - Casen (Drawer 4)
  - Chapin - Clemons (Drawer 5)
  - Clifford - Cunningham (Drawer 6)
  - Curtis - Dewey, H. (Drawer 7)
  - Dewey, I. - Dibble, Q (Drawer 8)
  - Dibble, R. - Fairchild (Drawer 9)
  - Fancher - Gardiner (Drawer 10)
  - Gates - Godard, L. (Drawer 11)
  - Godard, M. - Griffin, G. (Drawer 12)
  - Griffin, H. - Hawley (Drawer 13)
  - Hayden - Hayes, I. (Drawer 14)
  - Hayes, J. - Higley (Drawer 15)
  - Hills - Holcomb, B. (Drawer 16)
  - Holcomb, C. - Holcomb, G. (Drawer 17)
  - Holcomb, H. - Holcomb, M. (Drawer 18)
  - Holcomb, N. - Higgins (Drawer 19)
  - Hull - Korn (Drawer 20)
  - Lamson - Loomis, D. (Drawer 21)
  - Loomis, E. - Messenger, J. (Drawer 22)
  - Messenger, K. - Olmstead (Drawer 23)
  - O'Meara - Pettibone, O. (Drawer 24)
  - Pettibone, P. - Pilahowski (Drawer 25)
  - Pinney - Reed, L. (Drawer 26)
  - Reed, M. - Rogers, D. (Drawer 27)
  - Rogers, E. - Skinner, R. (Drawer 28)
  - Skinner, S. - Struthers (Drawer 29)
  - Sudbury - Viets, F. (Drawer 30)
  - Viets, G. - Weed, E. (Drawer 31)
  - Weed, F. - Wilcox (Drawer 32)
  - AWilder - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 33)
- Inventory Control Book, 1807-1925; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1913-004
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, circa 1925-1958; 11 cubic feet; T003290
  There is no index for this accession.
  - Abbey - Anteck (Box 1)
  - Benian - Callahan (Box 2)
  - Campbell - Clark, J. (Box 3)
  - Clark, K. - Cutter (Box 4)
  - Daniels - Forsyth (Box 5)
  - Fox - Godard, R. (Box 6)
  - Godard, S. - Guy (Box 7)
  - Halgreen - Holcomb, E. (Box 8)
  - Holcomb, F. - Janezyk (Box 9)
  - Jenkins - Long (Box 10)
  - Loomis - Messenger (Box 11)
  - Messerly - Parmelee, H. (Box 12)
  - Parmelee, I. - Rice, E. (Box 13)
  - Rice, F. - Shattuck, F. (Box 14)
  - Shattuck, G. - Tillotson (Box 15)
  - Tobey - Wilcox (Box 16)
  - AWilson - Z.; Miscellaneous (Box 17)
- Probate files, circa 1912-1975, bulk 1955-1975; 5 cubic feet; 2011-050
  - A - I (Box 1)
  - J - Miller, R.G. (Box 2)
  - Miller, Ronald - Shannon, E. (Box 3)
  - Shannon, J. - Z. (Box 4)
  - Unarranged (Box 5)
    Records in Box 5 are in 8 bundles.